Guide to the Stanford University Women's Club Records SC0494
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University Women's Club records
1896-2011
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Women's Club
SC0494
7 Linear Feet
The records include minutes, by-laws, financial records, annual reports, photographs, correspondence files, clippings, information booklets, and several publications sponsored by the Club.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The records were the gift of the Stanford University Women's Club.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Stanford Faculty Women's Club was formed in January 1896. Membership is open to female faculty, emeritae, and senior administrators and the wives and widows of faculty, emeriti, and senior administrators. The name was changed to the Stanford University Women's Club in 1992.
Description of the Collection
The records include minutes, by-laws, financial records, annual reports, photographs, correspondence files, clippings, information booklets, and several publications sponsored by the Club.
Women -- California -- Societies and clubs; Stanford University. Women's Club; Stanford University. Women's Club
- Records
  - Information Booklets, Faculty Women's Club, 1939-1957 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Information Booklets, 1957-1967 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Information Booklets, 1967-1992 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Mid-Peninsula Sourcery (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Preview (formerly Puff), 1966-1968 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Puff, 1963-1965 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Second Careers for Women..., 1971 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Bylaws, 1968, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Executive Board minutes, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Reports, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Executive Board minutes, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Section reports, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Childcare committee, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Executive Board minutes, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Committee on community involvement, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Executive Board minutes, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Executive Board minutes and reports, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Section and committee reports, 1971-72 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Records, assorted, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous records (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Committee on the Status of Women at Stanford, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Miner, Anne - memos from (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous publications and clippings, 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Preview, 1967-1971 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Sample mailing, 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Second careers workshop, brochures, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Space needs on campus, notes, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Business Wives - fashion shop program, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Child Care at Stanford (booklet) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "Gladys Kirkman, Stanford in Stitches," Stanford Magazine, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Preview, 1965-1969 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Preview, 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Preview, 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Preview, 1974-1976 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Preview, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Preview, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Preview, 1982-1985 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Preview, 1986-1990 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Tyler, Virgina, From the Heart and Other Places, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Additional Records, Accession ARCH-1998-131
  - 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Reports, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Samples of invitations; news items (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "Previews", 1969-1993 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Information booklet, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Information booklet, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Information booklet, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Information booklet, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Information booklet, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Information booklet, 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Information booklet, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Information booklet, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Information booklet, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Information booklet, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Information booklet, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Information booklet, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Information booklet, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Information booklet, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Information booklet, 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Information booklet, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Information booklet, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Information booklet, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Information booklet, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Information booklet, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Information booklet, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Information booklet, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Information booklet, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Information booklet, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Information booklet, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Information booklet, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Information booklet, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Information booklet, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Information booklet, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Stanford Faculty Women's Club Membership: President's File Copy, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Information booklet, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Information booklet, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Information booklet, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Information booklet, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Information booklet, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Information booklet, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Information booklet, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Information booklet, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Information booklet, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Information booklet, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Information booklet, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Information booklet, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Information booklet, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Information booklet, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Information booklet, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Information booklet, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Additional Records, Accession ARCH-1999-233
  - Interviews on SUWC (Box 1)
    - Elizabeth Sensabaugh, 1995 Aug 28
    - Ros Bacon, 1995 Jul 10
    - Jing Lyman, 1995 Nov 3
    - Connie Pratt, 1995 Nov 7
    - Eleanor Bark, 1995 Oct 23
    - Louise Herring, 1995 Aug 16
    - Gladys Kirkman, 1995 Sep 14
    - Lois Watt, 1995; 1 audiocassette(s)
  - Information and membership booklets, 1952-1998 (Box 1)
  - Clippings on members, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of eight members interviewed (see box 1 for the audio tapes), 1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Treasurer's journal, 1963-1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Notebook containing essays by members, with photographs, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
- Additional Records, 1960-2011; Accession ARCH-2012-003
  - Directory, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photograph Album (1 of 3), 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Photograph Album (2 of 3), 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photograph Album (3 of 3), 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photograph Album, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photograph Album, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photograph Album, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photograph Album, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photograph Album (1 of 2), 2002-2005 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photograph Album (2 of 2), 2002-2005 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Photograph Album (1 of 2), 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Photograph Album (2 of 2), 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Photograph Album (1 of 2), 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Photograph Album (2 of 2), 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Photographs, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Directory, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Historian's Notebook, Chairman's Report, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Photograph Album - Garden Section (1 of 2), 1993-2000 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Photograph Album - Garden Section (2 of 2), 1993-2000 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Minutes, 2010-2011 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Preview, 2010-2011 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Clippings and Photos (1 of 2), 1960s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Clippings and Photos (2 of 2), 1960s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 2)